<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Madeleine Ausburn</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Madeleine Ausburn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meet The Squad</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/10/meet-the-squad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/10/meet-the-squad/</guid>
      <description>  These are my two sheltie pups, Lila and Bowie!
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Python and R</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/10/using-python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/10/using-python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>Python and R languages in R Studio! Over the course of the semester, I have developed skills in both R and Python and am now able to have them both communicate in R Studio.
Using R language to evaluate the ‘iris’ dataset Below, I show how one can use R to evaluate a dataset, in this case the ‘iris’ dataset, and use the data to form meaningful plots. # Scatterplot of &amp;#39;iris&amp;#39; dataset comparing petal width to petal length by species library(ggplot2) iris &amp;lt;- iris ggplot(iris, aes(x=Petal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Data Wrangling and Exploration  Introduction The data that I acquired for this project was found on the University of Wisconsin Population Health Institute’s website, where I honed in on county health rankings. Because I intend on going to medical school and eventually becoming a doctor, I found health data to be of particular interest. More than this, however, I am passionate about educating myself on health disparities seen across different groups in our countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>This dataset, obtained through the ‘fivethirtyeight’ database, outlines each case of police killings in the United States during the year of 2015. The variables I chose to include are particular to each victim of said police killings: age, race/ethnicity, armed (whether or not they possessed a weapon at the time of their murder), the percentage of the population that was white, black or hispanic/latino in the area that the shooting took place, median household income of the area, poverty rates of the area, and proportion of college graduates in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madeleine&#39;s Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>  Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
